{
    "id": "8e0b50fbec0e458086702c48cf926c68",
    "title": "Present Perfect Or Present Perfect Continuous",
    "exercises": [
        {
            "id": "15661f0f88c744079f7091ed8a63f0c6",
            "title": "Present Perfect Or Present Perfect Continuous",
            "questions": [
                {
                    "question": "I ...................................... here for two weeks now.",
                    "description": "The present perfect continuous is used to talk about actions or situations that started in the past and has continued up to the present.",
                    "answers": [
                        "have worked",
                        "have been working"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "She .................................. to Dublin. You can't meet here now.",
                    "description": "Has gone is used to talk about incomplete visits. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "has gone",
                        "has been"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "She ................................. to Ireland so she knows that country.",
                    "description": "Has been is used to talk about completed visits.",
                    "answers": [
                        "has gone",
                        "has been"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "We ......................................... in this city for twenty-five years.",
                    "description": "The present perfect continuous is used to talk about actions or situations that started in the past and has continued up to the present.",
                    "answers": [
                        "have been living",
                        "are living"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "'You look tired.' 'Yes, I ..................................... for hours.'",
                    "description": "The present perfect continuous is used to talk about actions or situations that started in the past and has continued up to the present.",
                    "answers": [
                        "have run",
                        "have been running"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "I ........................................ a letter from him.",
                    "description": "The present perfect is commonly used to talk about recently finished actions and situations.",
                    "answers": [
                        "have just received",
                        "have been just received"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "He ..................................... any of the tasks I assigned to him.",
                    "description": "The present perfect is commonly used to talk about recently finished actions and situations.",
                    "answers": [
                        "has not finished",
                        "did not finish",
                        "has not been finishing"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "He ................................ IELTS test six times.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "took",
                        "has taken",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "I ...................................... reading the letters.",
                    "description": "The present perfect is used to talk about recently finished actions or situations.",
                    "answers": [
                        "have finished",
                        "finished",
                        "have been finishing"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "He ...................................... for a job for years.",
                    "description": "The present perfect continuous is used to talk about actions or situations that started in the past and has continued up to the present.",
                    "answers": [
                        "has looked",
                        "has been looking",
                        "is looking"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "Have you ever ................................... oysters?",
                    "description": "The third form of the verb is used after has and have.",
                    "answers": [
                        "ate",
                        "eat",
                        "eaten"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "I .................................. a lot about him.",
                    "description": "The present perfect is used to talk about finished events when there is no time reference.",
                    "answers": [
                        "have heard",
                        "heard"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                }
            ]
        }
    ]
}